Inventory of the Reed Family Papers 1899-1946
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Reed Family Papers 1899-1946 1910-1946
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2010.055
0.66
This collection contains the papers and biographic material, 1899-1946, of the Reed family of Floyd County, Virgina and Warren, Ohio. Included are personal letters and photographs, as well as records relating to service of family members in WWI and WWII. The correspondence series consists largely of personal letters written by Asa Daniel Reed to his future wife, Clarence Elizabeth Mangus (later Clarence Elizabeth Reed), during Reed's service in the U.S. Army. Reed's assignments included posts in the Philippines during the U.S. occupation thereof, in Texas along the border with Mexico, and in Germany and France during World War I. Interwar correspondences focus more on Clarence Reed's domestic life in Warren, Ohio. During the World War II period, Asa and Clarence Reed received correspondences from their son, Eugene Mangus Reed, serving in the U.S. Army. The biographic material series includes publications from the late nineteenth century on health remedies, as well as brief histories of the Ohio and Erie Railroads. The series also contains Asa D. Reed's discharge papers from the U.S. Army, the baby book of Eugene Mangus Reed, and a photograph of Clarence Mangus.
Reed family; Reed, Asa Daniel, Ca. 1888-unknown; Reed, Clarence Elizabeth, Unkown; Reed, Eugene Mangus, November 28, 1923-unknown arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 01/29/2010.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the papers and biographic material, 1899-1946, of the Reed family of Floyd County, Virgina and Warren, Ohio. Included are personal letters and photographs, as well as records relating to service of family members in WWI and WWII. The correspondence series consists largely of personal letters written by Asa Daniel Reed to his future wife, Clarence Elizabeth Mangus (later Clarence Elizabeth Reed), during Reed's service in the U.S. Army. Reed's assignments included posts in the Philippines during the U.S. occupation thereof, in Texas along the border with Mexico, and in Germany and France during World War I. Interwar correspondences focus more on Clarence Reed's domestic life in Warren, Ohio. During the World War II period, Asa and Clarence Reed received correspondences from their son, Eugene Mangus Reed, serving in the U.S. Army. The biographic material series includes publications from the late nineteenth century on health remedies, as well as brief histories of the Ohio and Erie Railroads. The series also contains Asa D. Reed's discharge papers from the U.S. Army, the baby book of Eugene Mangus Reed, and a photograph of Clarence Mangus.
Arrangement of Materials
Organized into two series: Series 1: Correspondence, Series 2: Biographic Material. Each series is arranged chronologically.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Photographs
Geographic Name:
Philippines--Description and travel.
Topical Term:
Postcards.; World War, 1914-1918--France; World War, 1914-1918--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Correspondence, 1910-1946; id65596
  - id66517 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1910-1912; id66518 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1913-1914; id66519 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1915; id66520 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, January-July 1916; id66521 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, August-December 1916; id66522 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, January-April 1917; id66523 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, May-July 1917; id66524 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, August-December 1917; id66525 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1918; id66526 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, January-June 1919; id66527 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, July-December 1919; id66528 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1920-1925; id66529 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - id66530 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1938; id66531 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1940-1942; id66532 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1944; id66533 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, undated; id66534 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, undated; id66535 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, undated; id66536 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, undated; id66537 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, undated; id66538 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Telegrams, 1911, 1925, 1928; id66539 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Postcards, 1914, 1921, 1941-1944; id66540 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Invitations, 1917-1946; id66541 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Greeting Cards, 1925-1940; id66542 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Biographic Material, circa 1899-1942; id65597
  - id66543 (Box 2)
    - Publications, 1899, 1901; id66544 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Military Material, 1920; id66545 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Baby Books, 1923; id66546 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Advertisements, 1931; id66547 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Railroad Materials, 1942; id66548 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Photographs, undated; id66549 (Box 2, Folder 18)